

JAMES WORWOOD

Senior Front-end Developer

- Harpenden, Hertfordshire, AL5 1HF
- **** 074 2333 3148
- ☑ james@worwood.co.za

Skills —
Angular 7+
Karma/Jasmine unit testing
Bootstrap
Angular Material
HTML
SCSS
Cypress
Danker

Summary

I am a self-driven software developer with 8 years of experience in helping to deliver projects on time and on budget. I have a special interest in understanding the needs of business and translating that into elegant solutions, and providing a valuable product for the end-users. My focus for the last 3 years has been in front-end development specifically Angular 7+, CSS, HTML, Angular material, Bootstrap, and a few other technologies. I have a special interest for the dev-ops realm as well, with some experience in Docker, Jenkins,

Azure, Kubernetes

Work experience

2021-11 - Senior Front-end Engineer

2023-07 EBRD(European Bank of Reconstruction and Development)

My main focus when joining the team was to to help deliver new features and develop their micro front-end **single-spa** application as well as continue build on their already existing **component library**. I also continued to grow the unit **test coverage to 80%** across all applications that our team owned using **Karma** and **Jasmine**. I was then included in upgrading all applications to latest angular and then migrating all micro front-end applications from single-spa to **Module Federation**(25 different micro front-ends), while still maintaining single-spa functionality until the work had been complete at which time we could turn off the single-spa container application. My role included helping other developers across 5 international teams within the bank to deliver features and maintain code quality as well as helping out with devlops issues such as ingress files not being setup correctly or broken Jenkins pipelines. I often helped with releases, and end user support issues which included investigating Kibana logs and exploring potential data issues. During my time at EBRD I also setup **Cypress E2E tests** as well as intergrate them as part of our build pipelines when releasing applications to testing environments.

2021-05 - Senior Front-end Engineer

2021-08 Vashi, Central London

I joined the team with goal to take over the project from a consulting company with the view of a like for like green pastures re-write from what was implemented with the 3rd party consulting company. My focus was shared between the front-end infrastructure and the feature team. My day to day responsibility varied from things such as optimizing our webpack configurations. fixing build profiles, to helping get features finished on time, defect resolution as well as some business facing support

2020-08 - Senior Front-end Engineer

2021-05 Gama Aviation, Farmborough, UK

I joined the core engineering team with my main focus in developing key features needed to complete sales pipelines. I helped set and maintain development standards for our integrations with 3rd party services as well as our backend teams. I have also helped in creating standards and wikis for onboarding new developers and helping full stack developers understand our way of working. I also played a key role in bug support.

2020-02 - Senior Front-end Engineer

2020-08 MYHSM, Berkshire, Aylesbury

I joined the team in early stages of project creation. I played a key role in developing core features for the company's portal application which their customers would be using to secure their transactions. My focus was developing customer facing features in Angular using Angular Material/Bootstrap, talking RESTful services exposed by the PHP Laravel backend. I worked very closely with the business units to successfully release the portal into production.

2017-10 - Full-stack Developer

2019-10 Medscheme, Johannesburg, ZA

I was asked to join the project to assist in completing an Angular, Spring Boot Java project that was behind schedule. My responsibilities were to ascertain what functionality was business critical and help complete critical functionality in order to deliver a working product on time. The project was successfully delivered on time in April 2018 at which time we focused on stabilising the application and finishing other functionality, the project went into maintenance mode from October 2018.

The teams next project was to re-develop the main call centre application. My role was creating the projects in Bitbucket, Dockerizing them, setting up the Docker registry and deploying to Kubernetes pods using the Jenkins build pipelines to automate our builds and deployments to each environment. I also helped in breaking up the logic for the different business units that would be using the different application areas into separate API layer projects. We created a container project for the front end Angular project using Git Submodules, this allowed for all teams to develop in parallel, making reusable components, and create a uniform styling for the entire application.

In January 2019 I was asked to help out another team within the organisation, in rescuing a project as it was running behind schedule.

They had already purchased a product to manage and master the data we were injesting, so they were de-compiling the code to be able to modify it in a way that would provide a meaningful solution to the business. This was a master-data-management type project, and this was adding unnecessary complexity. We decided to only use the product to manage the storage of data, and develop our own Spring Boot REST Services layer to integrate with a new Angular front end project that we could be incorporated into the greater container project that I mentioned earlier. I developed the Angular components, helped with some of the styling throughout the application. I managed all of the DevOps for the team, which included creating the Java EE/SE front end project, creating the Jenkins pipelines, Dockerizing the applications and creating deployments and pods for Kubernetes.

2017-04 - Full-stack Developer

2017-10 Standard Bank, Johannesburg, ZA

Gauteng

I was asked to join the USSD team to help them implement further services that they wanted to bring into their USSD application. I wrote code to consume RESTful services from external suppliers such as the National Lottery. I was in charge of making sure that the team deployments happened in a timely manner, getting sign off from our formal testing environments, presenting production deployments at the CAB meetings and then implementing the solution into our production environments as well as getting final sign off once the solution was live.

2014-09 - Full-stack Developer

2017-03 Wesbank, Johannesburg, ZA

During my time at Wesbank I was involved in a few different projects. My first project was to help develop and deploy an e-commerce ADF application into WebCenter and WebLogic. I was involved in the development styling and defect resolution. This project was successfully completed and then it was decided to re-write the application again, but this time into Java EE. I was part of the team that redesigned the entire system and developed it to use a JSF front-end incorporating Bootstrap to style our pages. We broke up the back end projects into different layers and developed them using SOAP services. This allowed us to expose a single API layer that we can then, from different projects, consume services from. Wesbank was a division of the First Rand Group, which had a brother bank called FNB. They wanted to consume some of these services and I was included in the team tasked to expose certain services from our API layer to group level infrastructure. This allowed them to securely call our backend services and allowed them to add functionality to their different banking apps. My role was also implementing continuous integration with Jenkins for all of our different projects. I did the migrations from Artifactory to Nexus. I also did end of line support for most of the applications that fell under our teams realm.

2014-02 - Developer

2014-08 REDISA, Johannesburg, ZA

Having successfully taken this product to production, the stakeholders decided to rewrite the entire system using the Fusion Middleware stack. My role was to help build what was originally done in PHP into ADF, and then deploy the working application into WebCenter where I was able to then skin the application before also documenting and providing training manuals for the new system.

2013-09 - Junior Developer

2014-01 Gijima, Johannesburg, ZA

This was a government project that allowed users to be able to purchase information online about their properties, such as ordering a deed to their land, or getting ERF numbers. My role was to assist the team in developing the application using the Oracle Fusion Middleware stack. We developed the application using Oracle Database, ADF(Application Development Framework) and WebCenter with some BPM.

2012-08 - Junior Developer

2013-08 REDISA, Johannesburg, ZA

This was a government funded start-up company that created infrastructure to recycle and reuse tyres. My main role was to help develop business solutions and then transform them into working modules for a greater web application. The front end was mainly coded in PHP and JavaScript, run on an Apache server with an underlying Oracle database.

Education

- 2014 Bachelor of Information Technology

Monash

Monash University Bachelors of Information Technology

(Application Development & Networking)

- 2011 Diploma

Summit College Matric

2011 Summit College Matric (IEB)

2012 Diploma Software Engineering (IEEE)

Certifications

• Oracle Java 8 certified associate (OCAJP)

Formal Training

- Course with Jernej Kruse(Oracle international)
- Completed a Practical training course with iLab
- iLab course in emotional and public speaking
- iLab course in project management
- Formal Angular training
- Formal Docker training